Guide to the Midsummer Mozart Festival Collection ARS.0066
Archive of Recorded Sound
Midsummer Mozart Festival Collection
1975-1995
ARS.0066
Hubbard, Harry
15 boxes: 289 10.5" open reel tapes, two document boxes of programs
Archive of Recorded Sound
Two hundred eighty-nine (289) open-reel tape recordings of performances from the Midsummer Mozart Festival, together with programs and tape logs, from 1975 to 1995.
Access
Open for research; material must be requested at least two business days in advance of intended use. Contact the Archive for assistance.
Source
The Midsummer Mozart Festival Collection was donated to the Stanford Archive of Recorded Sound by Robert Hubbard in November 2006.
Scope and Contents
Two hundred eighty-nine (289) open-reel tape recordings of performances from the Midsummer Mozart Festival, together with programs and tape logs, from 1975 to 1995. The annual event, begun in 1974 by George Cleve, remains the only concert series in North America devoted exclusively to the works of Wolfgang Amadeus Mozart. Taking place in various venues around the greater San Francisco Bay Area (from Sonoma to San Jose), the festival attracts soloists from around the world, who join talented local musicians and Cleve himself on stage. The tapes were recorded and extensively annotated by Harry Hubbard, and the collection was donated by his son Robert.
Arrangement
Tapes are in approximate chronological order. A contents list, in the form of handwritten logs, is included, but the printed programs offer the most information about performances.
Indexing Terms
Midsummer Mozart Festival Orchestra.; Mozart, Wolfgang Amadeus, 1756-1791; Live sound recordings; Music festivals--California; San Francisco Bay Area (Calif.)
- 1. Open reel tapes
  - 1., 1975-1980 (Box 1, Box 2)
  - 2., 1977-1979 (Box 3)
  - 3., 1979-1983 (Box 4)
  - 4., 1984-1985 (Box 5)
  - 5., 1985-1987 (Box 6)
  - 6., 1987-1988 (Box 7)
  - 6., 1987-1988 (Box 7)
  - 7., 1988-1989 (Box 8)
  - 8., 1989-1990, 1993 (Box 9)
  - 9., 1990-1992 (Box 10)
  - 10., 1992-1993 (Box 11)
  - 11., 1994-1995 (Box 12)
  - 12., 1995 (Box 13)
  - Miscellaneous non-festival tapes, Nineteen 7" reels (Box 13)
- 2. Documentation
  - Correspondence (Box 14)
  - Master Lists and Tape Logs (handwritten logs) (Box 14)
  - Annotated programs, 1975-1987 (Box 14)
  - Annotated programs, 1988-1995 (Box 15)